The untold story of the wild west.
Posse is a action, adventure, western film directed by Mario Van Peebles.
A group of mostly black infantrymen return from the
Spanish-American War with a cache of gold.
They travel to the West where their leader searches
for the men who lynched his father.
Jesse Lee, played by Mario Van Peebles.
Jimmy J. 'Little J' Teeters, played by Stephen Baldwin.
Obobo, played by Tommy Lister Jr..
Father Time, played by Big Daddy Kane.
Colonel Graham, played by Billy Zane.
Phoebe, played by Pam Grier.
Posse is a 1993 American  Western film directed by
and starring Mario Van Peebles.
Featuring a large ensemble cast, the film tells the story of a posse of African-American
soldiers and one ostracized white soldier, who are all betrayed by a corrupt colonel.
The story starts with the group escaping with a cache of gold, and continues with their leader Jesse
Lee (Mario Van Peebles) taking revenge on the men who killed his preacher father.
The story is presented as a flashback told by an unnamed old man (Woody Strode).
The title of the film refers to a group of people who are
summoned to help law enforcement officers.
This film was the first to be released by Gramercy Pictures.
Melvin Van Peebles, the father of director Mario Van Peebles,
recorded a new song, "Cruel Jim Crow", for the film.
This marked his first music recording in 20 years, after his
1974 album What the....You Mean I Can't Sing?!
It led to the production of a new album, Ghetto Gothic, released in 1995.
The film takes the form of an extended memory, as told by Woody
Strode, who witnessed some of the events as a young boy.
Strode's opening narration, documenting early black settlers, continues his onscreen naming
of individuals overlooked by history from the 1972 documentary Black Rodeo.
The film explores themes of shootout, racial tension, gun fight.